JAMES FARRELL SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

EXPERIENCE

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Student of Cohort 30 Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp

- Skilled in Javascript, CSS3, HTML5, and ReactJS as well as styling libraries such as Bootstrap, Reactstrap, and Materialize. Implemented packages from NPM and deployed projects to Github and Heroku.
- Worked in teams to develop complex modularized webapplications. Learned to delegate tasks and coordinate pull requests using Github.
- Chewsy 2019 ReactJs, Reactstrap, Auth0

Chewsy helps you break away from anonymous restaurant reviews and ratings by using Yelp's Fusion API to show you a single, random restaurant image at a time. Built in React.js, styled with Reactstrap, and authenticated with Auth0, Chewsy takes all the impersonal data out of a your next restaurant search and reduces it down to one simple question... What looks good to YOU. After logging in through Auth0, you're asked to submit your location and up to 3 food categories provided directly from Yelp. When submitted you are presented with one image of an actual restaurant dish thanks again to Yelp's Fusion API. And because it's only one at a time, you aren't crowded with decisions. Instead, you are free to "pass left" until you find something that looks appetizing. Find something you love? Click the smiley face to be presented with information on the restaurant and the opportunity to favorite and review it for yourself. You'll be surprised at what tempts your tastebuds.

TEST KITCHEN STUDIOS

Freelance Music Producer and Studio Owner | June 2016 - present

- Produced original music for Heaven's Door's 2018 online advertising campaign.
- Produced, engineered, and performed on multiple singles for many emerging artists.

QUEST OF THE MUSCLE NERD

Film Composer | June 2018 - December 2018

- Scored, engineered, performed, and mixed original music for the feature length documentary Quest of the Muscle Nerd.
- Film is currently in the final stage of production.

PROFESSIONAL KEYBOARDIST

Touring Musician for Major Label Artists | 2010 - 2016

- Brett Eldredge | January 2014 January 2016
- David Nail | January 2012 January 2014
- Matt Nathanson | January 2010 January 2012

CONTACT DETAILS

939 Seymour Ave, Nashville, TN, 37206 USA (312) 576-5666 hellojamesfarrell.com james@hellojamesfarrell.com linkedIn: @james-w-farrell github: @farrellkat

ABOUT

Before I was a developer, I was a musician. I wasn't a famous frontman. I didn't headline. I was a working musician. Which means like many coders, I had to be creative under pressure, meet tight deadlines, and collaborate with all personality types at all hours. Over 11 years, I learned how to be a professional and to treat every show, whether empty or standing-room only, like Radio City. And to make every client feel like a star. In the end, I didn't leave music. I became a coder for the same reason I started touring: I love the work.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School - Full Stack Development Bootcamp

- January 2019 - Present / Certificate

Berklee College of Music - BA Contemporary

Writing and Production

VOLUNTEER WORK

Words and Music - Country Music Hall of Fame

Mentored a young aspiring songwriter and produced and performed his original song for his class and for the Hall of Fame.

Berklee College of Music - Nashville Trip

Sat on an alumni panel to teach students about life as a professional musician, living in Nashville. Spent time fielding questions and staying in touch with some students outside of the event.